<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Who am I? on Cupper</title>
    <link>https://www.deepaksurti.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Who am I? on Cupper</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 12:47:02 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.deepaksurti.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://www.deepaksurti.com/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.deepaksurti.com/projects/</guid>
      <description>A listing of my projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review and clean up</title>
      <link>https://www.deepaksurti.com/series/expense-calc/06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2005 12:47:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.deepaksurti.com/series/expense-calc/06/</guid>
      <description>Till session 5, we implemented all 6 requirements. Time to take a look at the code keeping in mind the observations of the last session.
First up I add more test coverage for other scenarios. Everything works fine.
But i had pointed out about making parellel class heirarchies of expense sheet and expense statement. I try doing it but when i realize the Factory Method signatures would be different I revert back to old desing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generating expense statement for a payer</title>
      <link>https://www.deepaksurti.com/series/expense-calc/05/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2005 12:47:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.deepaksurti.com/series/expense-calc/05/</guid>
      <description>Now having implemented 4 requirements I come on to the next one:
Requirement 5: Generate an expense statement for a payer for a date range.
Say for bhavdeep for 1 Apr to 30 Apr 2005 genrate an expense statement should look like this:
Bhavdeep 1 Apr 2005 to 30 Apr 2005
 Bhavdeep receive from Surender 13 USD Bhavdeep receive from Deepak 5 USD 2 Apr 2005 Albertsons Deepak 12 USD 7 Apr 2005CostCo Surender 5 USD 16 Apr 2005 Burger King Deepak -7USD 28 Apr 2005 Panda Express Surender 8 USD  Thus we see a header with name, date range for statement, summary, and details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generating expense statements</title>
      <link>https://www.deepaksurti.com/series/expense-calc/04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2005 12:47:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.deepaksurti.com/series/expense-calc/04/</guid>
      <description>In session 1, we implemented requirements 1 and 2. And sessions 2, 3 we spent time simplifying the design. At this stage we are now good enough to move on to implementing the next requirement.
Requirement 3: Generate an expense sheet for a payer for a list of transactions for a date range.
Steps: Wriet junit test case. While writing the test case I realize I have not added a date to transactoins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simplifying transactions and expenses</title>
      <link>https://www.deepaksurti.com/series/expense-calc/03/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2005 12:47:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.deepaksurti.com/series/expense-calc/03/</guid>
      <description>The tools I am using are:
 Intellij Idea 4.5.3 CVS for source control *its a local repository on my laptop Argo UML for class diagrams. I just used visual paradigm for session 1 but argo is what i m more comfortable with.  Till now the implementation looks good enough and more importantly simple. Now when I look at the expense sheet generated for the transaction it looks somehting like this for req 1: (see session 1)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simplifying Party Hierarchy</title>
      <link>https://www.deepaksurti.com/series/expense-calc/02/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2005 12:47:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.deepaksurti.com/series/expense-calc/02/</guid>
      <description>Simplifying Party heirarchy</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started</title>
      <link>https://www.deepaksurti.com/series/expense-calc/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2005 12:40:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.deepaksurti.com/series/expense-calc/01/</guid>
      <description>Setup, implementing 2 basic features</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hibernate Mappings &amp; Encapsulated Collections</title>
      <link>https://www.deepaksurti.com/hibernate-mappings-collections/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2005 05:13:32 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.deepaksurti.com/hibernate-mappings-collections/</guid>
      <description>Collections must be encapsulated . Also I am using Hibernate as the persistence solution. I have a uni-directional many to many relationship between Parent and Child. My java code looks like this:
Parent { String name; Set children = new HashSet(); public void getChildren() { return Collections.unmodifiableCollection(children); } private void setChildren(Set children) { this.children = children; } public void addChild(Child obj) { ///..... } public void removeChild(Child obj) { ///.... } } Child { String name; //.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Desk</title>
      <link>https://www.deepaksurti.com/my-desk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2005 10:17:15 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.deepaksurti.com/my-desk/</guid>
      <description>When its so tidy..chances are I may not be at work :-)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Agile</title>
      <link>https://www.deepaksurti.com/using-agile/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2005 02:28:54 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.deepaksurti.com/using-agile/</guid>
      <description>The past 3 yrs or so I have learnt a lot of lessons, most of which are &amp;ldquo;how to write better software&amp;rdquo;. &amp;hellip;
The challenge in front of me is to, at every given opportunity (with a change of perception I realize these are infinite) use agile practices.
Why do I want to use agile practices? ¶ Most importantly using agile practices makes my life less stressful and work infinte fun :-)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automated Tests</title>
      <link>https://www.deepaksurti.com/automated-tests/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2005 12:47:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.deepaksurti.com/automated-tests/</guid>
      <description>I was asked to write this utility to convert a graph of objects of type &amp;lsquo;X&amp;rsquo; into type &amp;lsquo;Y&amp;rsquo;. The difference between X and Y is that X objects sit in a layer whereas Y travel all over the network.
I was already handed out some partly written code. I was happy because I am training myself to be an agile practitioner and reading, working on someone else&amp;rsquo;s code should be easy for me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing Mindset</title>
      <link>https://www.deepaksurti.com/changing-mindset/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2005 05:12:32 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.deepaksurti.com/changing-mindset/</guid>
      <description>In an earlier post I had pointed out use of TDD and Refactoring to write the domain logic for poll measurements.
Key activities still were to be done:
 Persist this data onto database. Create views to play with this data.  You may have guessed I believe in working demos. Not html prototypes. I want to see in code that I can do it atleast in 1 way what I or you claim to be possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Business Knowledge and Software Projects</title>
      <link>https://www.deepaksurti.com/business-knowledge-and-software-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2005 07:07:31 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.deepaksurti.com/business-knowledge-and-software-projects/</guid>
      <description>Often in every other project, we can hear the following whispers..at times they get too loud. Developers: We are not getting requirments right. Typically the expecatation is from requirement gatherers. Requirement gatherers: Customer is not able to give requirments clearly. Typically expectation is from customer. So the flow usually is from developers -&amp;gt; requirement gatherers -&amp;gt; customers. This happens on development projects.
You may note I have not mentioned business analysts/functional/domain experts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading Styles</title>
      <link>https://www.deepaksurti.com/reading-styles/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2005 07:53:59 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.deepaksurti.com/reading-styles/</guid>
      <description>Reading a Newspaper  Reading a Comprehension Piece  Reading a Book  Details Awareness   Here&amp;rsquo;s a sample of how I read. Basically how I approach. Please note that these are only general tips and you will need to make changes as per your requirments.
Reading a Newspaper ¶ The articles of interest for me are typically columns, edits and analysis types. (You may see I have an Indian Express hangover :-).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Access Specifiers</title>
      <link>https://www.deepaksurti.com/java-access-specifiers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2005 12:48:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.deepaksurti.com/java-access-specifiers/</guid>
      <description>So many times there is confusion about java and its access specifers. Here’s what they mean once and for all.
Public: Available to all wherever you may be.
Private: Available only to me.
Protected: Available to my derived types.
Friend: Available to all who belong to my group (package) i.e. are my friends.
Naturally, if I make a class private it can’t be accessed by anyone except the class itself! Now trying make a class protected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Refactoring Helps</title>
      <link>https://www.deepaksurti.com/why-refactoring-helps/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2005 05:43:38 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.deepaksurti.com/why-refactoring-helps/</guid>
      <description>Take a look.
I had this requirment:
We conduct polls (which can be looked at like permanent polls). We gather monthly statistics. We want to :
 find out votes cast till a month say Jun 2005 find out votes cast for a quarter of a finanical year say Quarter 1 for 2004 - 2005 find out votes cast for a half yearly of a financial year say half year 1 for 2004 - 2005 find out votes cast for a fin year say 2004 - 2005.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No New Year Resolutions</title>
      <link>https://www.deepaksurti.com/no-new-year-resolutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2005 05:25:34 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.deepaksurti.com/no-new-year-resolutions/</guid>
      <description>Every time a new year dawns and people come up with resolutions. Though I am not the kind of person who can do it with resolutions. I cannot decide anything at the spur of a moment and go for it. I though must point out that I apply this constraint to professional matters ;-)
The problem I find with resolutions is that there is not sufficient thought thats gone behind it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Tips</title>
      <link>https://www.deepaksurti.com/learning-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Dec 2004 02:43:31 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.deepaksurti.com/learning-tips/</guid>
      <description>Learning I believe never stops. Only the rate of learning. If you are conscious about your learning, great. But the biggest change comes about when people get into jobs. Somehow there is the impression, once again from the mechanical industry, that your learning, education is where you spend time learning. And the fruit of that is a job where you are not supposed to learn.
But the knowledge industry has changed that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IIM Cat 2004</title>
      <link>https://www.deepaksurti.com/iim-cat-2004/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2004 12:06:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.deepaksurti.com/iim-cat-2004/</guid>
      <description>Why the big fuss? That questions carry unequal marks, we dont know the proportion of negative marks etc. CAT = Certainly Abnormal Test. CAT 2004 for sure made everyone realize what to expect &amp;ldquo;Dont expect&amp;rdquo; ;-)
Anyways a huge change was anticipated. How short our memories are? CAT 2003 was held again in Feb 2004 because some Don played Cat and Mouse with the IIMs reputation. So the lion had to roar back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personality Types Xp</title>
      <link>https://www.deepaksurti.com/personality-types-xp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2004 12:29:26 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.deepaksurti.com/personality-types-xp/</guid>
      <description>I was going through a chapter of Norman Lewis Reading Faster. Here he talks about personality types and their reading habits. And immediately I started to think if there is a link between personality types and XP. Because what is XP but a set of habits that people on the Xp project have. Habit of writing tests first, habit of automating tests, habit of domain design, habit of integrating continuously. Habits and more habits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Xp Inflection Point</title>
      <link>https://www.deepaksurti.com/xp-inflection-point/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2004 09:53:59 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.deepaksurti.com/xp-inflection-point/</guid>
      <description>The other day I was reading Andrew S Grooves &amp;ldquo;Only the Paranoid Survive&amp;rdquo;. This book basically talks about those points one faces in career or buisiness ( I know nothing there) which do a volte-face. Everything that seemed so right till yesterday has changed completely.
Andrew talks about PC and Internet, the two inflection points which have impacted both careers and business in a profound way. And he also says that to handle these crisis points or strategic inflection points, one needs always to be on the alert and keep experimenting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Will</title>
      <link>https://www.deepaksurti.com/i-will/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2004 01:30:34 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.deepaksurti.com/i-will/</guid>
      <description>While reading how to read better and faster by Norman Lewis, I learnt a big lesson. Which I had learnt earlier also. But then its always good to revise. The difference between &amp;ldquo;will&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;wish&amp;rdquo;. I realized that in many projects we say &amp;ldquo;wish we had automated tests, wish we had continous builds&amp;rdquo; etc. But we dont anything. Why? Because we dont really want to change or are &amp;ldquo;will&amp;quot;ing to put the efforts and bear the pain of change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading Better Faster</title>
      <link>https://www.deepaksurti.com/reading-better-faster/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2004 05:46:37 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.deepaksurti.com/reading-better-faster/</guid>
      <description>Of late I am back to getting skilled at my interest of reading. Reading is one of the best ways to keep one informed. And to keep yourself informed, you also need to read a variety of material. People I find who read a variety of material are those who have developed good reading habits.
To develop these habits for self, I picked what else but the Reading Manual by Norman Lewis.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
